Arin?
Arin, are you okay?
[Arin]
Mom, Dad, I'm so sorry.
I wanted to find you,
but I failed.
I can't do anything right.
Arin, what are
you talking about?
[Arin] Lloyd? Nya?
[Riyu groans]
What happened to you?
Ras happened.
I saved someone named Bonzle
from that Imperium
science girl,
but Ras showed up
out of nowhere
and took Bonzle back.
I did everything I could.
Ras still plowed right
through me like I was nothing.
Do you know where Ras is now?
Strike the Gong of Shattering,
prepare the ritual.
Looks like the boss
cleaned up your mistake.
[Jordana groans]
[Kai] Shh, it's Kai.
I'm gonna melt your shackle.
[suspenseful music]
[gong echoes]
[Kai groans]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a Ninja
for what's right ♪
[flames roar]
-[gong echoes]
-[choir vocalizes]
[Sorceress grunts]
Ow. Now I remember
why I never ride you, Hatty.
[grunts] Come on!
We gotta get Bonzle back
from Ras and the Wolf...
Where are Ras and his army?
And have you seen our friend?
She's about this tall.
Also, a skeleton.
Haven't seen her! And Ras
set our island to crash!
[suspenseful music]
[chains clink]
What! No thank you for
the all-powerful Gandeleria?
There's gotta be a way to stop
this thing from crashing!
Is there a motor room?
[gear creaks]
It would seem
repairs are in order.
Good thing I brought my tools.
[heroic music]
[Cole grunts]
[gong echoes]
[Ninjas groan]
The secret
enchantments, Lord Ras.
Your pronunciation must be--
Do not worry about my part.
It will be perfect.
Are you prepared to revert
this spell and summon the Five?
[sighs]
Yes, I will be able to
completely control this spell.
[Bonzle] I'm not just
a spell! I'm a person!
Quiet!
No more mistakes.
Theo'do'nox cataline no dox ret
so ana-ton go so-lox
anitatatay-poxel.
No'verix catalo
ana-ton re-ingalago
so-lox niver-maste
fo le pezotan...
[Wyldfyre groans]
These masks are the worst!
Hold still, my aim is perfect!
[Kai] Wait, are you sure you--
[yells]
Nice. [sniffs]
Wait, does anyone
smell burnt hair?
-[flame roars]
-[Cinder] Intruders!
-[gasps]
-[Kai grunts]
Stop the Ninja from
freeing the prisoners!
We need sacrifices!
[continues chanting]
Ready for some
Rising Dragon Technique, Kai?
Uh, anytime now.
I'm connecting
my internal movement
to the movement
of the universe,
like we were taught.
No, you're standing still.
Okay, look, I only did
Rising Dragon once, by accident.
I'm not sure I can do it again.
New plan.
You fight the Wolf Masks,
and I keep Cinder
from Shatterspinning.
Now, that I can do!
[dramatic music]
[clanking and crashing]
[Wyldfyre grunts]
[Cinder growls]
[Cinder grunts]
[Cinder groans]
You think I didn't
expect your smoke form?
[Cinder grunts]
[Bonzle] No! Please!
[suspenseful music]
-[chains clink]
-There you go!
You can thank Wyldfyre
for your freedom.
[flames roar]
[Kai] Don't these
clowns feel any pain?
[Kai grunts]
[flames roar]
[heroic music]
Kai! Need a hand?
[shackles clank]
Ready to join the fight!
No! You're all some kinda
sacrifices or something.
Ras can't finish his plan
without you, so get outta here!
Leber-lox menoo-gala
het regalo.
Poxel da in-therox lef belent
mil-troton sempaste
guthero-vix to!
No!
[suspenseful music]
[gateway roars]
Oh, no!
The gateway is open!
Bring the sacrifices!
What? Don't let them escape!
[Wyldfyre]
No monks for you!
[Cinder grunts]
[Sora groans]
[yells]
[mech beeps]
[Kai yells]
[Kai grunts]
Eat fire!
[Wyldfyre grunts]
Come on, do you really
want Cinder back?
This guy is a grade-A jerk!
[Cinder grunts]
If we're going down, Kai,
we're going down together,
like the fire-breathing
dragons we are!
[Lloyd] Ninja, go!
-[Nya] You okay?
-Of course.
Kai and I had this
totally under control.
[Kai groans]
Arin! I was afraid
you went down with the Bounty!
[Arin] Riyu flew us to safety.
What? He can't fly.
We trained and-- Oop!
I stand corrected.
Baka-lu. Poxel da
in-therox lef belent
mil-troton sempaste
guthero-vix to.
Cinder! Finish this!
[Cinder grunts]
[groans]
Oh no!
[Sora yells]
[Sora groans]
[Arin] Sora, get up!
She's unconscious?
Aw, too bad.
She'll miss my
sweet Shatterspin.
[Cinder growls]
[Arin] Ninja! Don't
let Cinder get that mask!
[Cinder groans]
[flames roar]
[chuckles]
Fine, that's
not the only mask!
I will shatter the last
dregs of goodness in my soul!
[Cinder laughs]
[gong echoes]
[Cinder grunts]
-We have to stop this!
-[Nya] We can't.
-[Wyldfyre groans]
-[Riyu roars]
[Riyu grunts]
[Nya grunts]
-What is that?
-It's Kai!
[Cinder grunts]
[heroic music]
Rising Dragon Technique?
Impossible!
[Ras grunts]
[Kai] Nice trick, right?
Wanna see more?
[Ras growls]
You are too late!
The ritual is nearly complete!
[Ras groans]
[Lloyd] Your Shatterspin
warrior's met his match,
and the Blood Moon's
almost passed.
Even your sacrifices are gone!
Yeah, I'd say the ritual's
almost over, and you failed!
All I need for a sacrifice
is an un-shattered soul.
And I know just who to use.
[Kai yells]
[grunting, groaning]
[Nya] Kai!
[Riyu grunts]
[Kai] No!
[Nya] No!
Huh?
Finally,
after long centuries...
I'm free.
[suspenseful music]
Hold on! I'll get you a rope!
Close enough.
[Cole grunts]
It won't budge.
[metal creaks]
[grunts, groans]
It might not have to.
If you could hold
the bottom of the wheel
and reach the top mechanism,
your mech could effectively
act as a new wheel assembly
and right the kingdom.
[Cole groans]
[Cole]
My mech is too small.
I can't reach
the ceiling mechanism!
If there was only a method
of increasing your mech's size.
[gasps] Hold that thought!
But I'm not a mechanic!
What could you
possibly need me for?
As much as I hate to say it,
we need you to use your
size-changing spell on me.
[grunting]
Come on, Zane!
You got this!
[suspenseful music]
Oh, this is bad!
It seems
to have gotten easier,
like someone is helping me!
It's working!
You've almost
straightened it out!
[grunts]
Oh, no.
I did not factor in
this part of the spell.
Hold on!
We are going to crash!
[groans]
[heroic music]
[sighs]
[gasps] Oh, my.
We didn't fall?
-Zane, we did it!
-Did we?
[grunts]
Something's happening.
Losing control!
I am the one responsible
for your release.
And I intend
to free the others,
using them as sacrifices!
Whatever it takes.
[Ninjas yell]
[Nya] This is for Kai!
[whooshing]
[Nya yells, grunts]
-[groans]
-[all exclaim]
[Lloyd grunts]
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Not now, please.
[groans, pants]
Rontu told me
I can't force the universe
to bend to my will.
I have to find
my place in its current,
allow the visions
to come, to flow.
[dramatic music]
[Lloyd grunts]
Oh, come on!
Aah! This can't be possible!
The spell's fighting me!
It's trying to shut the gate!
Keep that gate open!
[Bonzle]
Red Ninja, wake up!
[Kai grunts]
Wha--
Who is that? Where am I?
[Bonzle] I'm the spell
Ras is using
to keep the gateway open.
The Ninja are fighting so hard.
I think I can help them
and can shut the gate down
before the rest of the
Forbidden Five come through.
What do you need me to do?
[Bonzle] You've gotta get
back to the other side
before I shut the gate,
or you'll be trapped
in here forever.
I don't know how to do that.
I'll try to find a way out,
but if you get a chance
to close that gate, close it.
Don't worry about me!
[Nya grunts]
I'll knock the sacrifices
in there myself!
[grunts]
[Arin] No, not Nya too!
Huh?
[Arin] Come on,
object-Spinjitzu.
You gotta work this time!
[grunts]
[grunting]
[gasps]
I did it! I did it!
[Arin cheers]
That wasn't Arin.
-You used your tech powers to--
-Shh.
[Jordana grunts]
[gasps]
[Nya] No!
Kai is still in there!
Master!
I call for your aid!
[Lloyd] Huh?
[all gasp]
[Arin] So did we win?
[gentle music]
[stone cracks]
The Blood Moon has passed.
Our curse is over.
The world is still here.
Maybe the Ninja didn't mess up.
[grunts]
What?
How did--
Where are we?
How dare you?
You cut and run before
you got the other four out!
[grunts] You will not
speak to me like that, Nokt.
You owe your freedom to me.
[grunts]
[Nokt screams]
I expect loyalty.
And my control device
will guarantee I get it.
And you!
You failed to keep
the portal open, Jordana!
-[grunting]
-[Nokt groans]
Do you hear me, Jord--
[yells]
[celestial whirring]
Yes, my master.
I understand.
This was just one
step in the plan,
but far from the only one.
[celestial whirring]
I will not fail you.
We will still conquer
the Tournament of the Sources
and dominate the Source Dragons.
Then all the power
you need will be yours.
[Cole gasps]
Nothing in the archive explains
what you saw happen
at the Shadow Dojo
or where it might have gone.
But this much I do know, we
cannot thank you enough, Ninja.
You have much to celebrate.
Why don't I feel
like celebrating?
I would never have admitted
it when I was a kid,
but my big brother
was always my hero.
Now he's the world's hero.
[sighs] Again.
[both sob]
[Zane]
Bonzle is gone too.
It appears she used the last
of her magic to battle Jordana
and close the gate.
I'm so proud of her.
She was a such
a selfless little spell.
No, she was a selfless person.
Great job, Arin.
Knocking out Ras with
your object spinjitzu
is what brought
the ritual to an end.
We couldn't have
done it without you.
I gotta admit, after
my mess-up training,
I started to wonder if I even
belonged on the team anymore.
But pulling out a win today
really meant a lot to me.
[eerie music]
[Bonzle]
Hey. It's okay. It's me.
[gasps] That voice.
You're the spell?
The voice I heard?
I closed the gate.
Most of the Forbidden Five
couldn't cross over.
But now we're both trapped here.
I'm so sorry.
No apology needed.
You did good, kid.
I didn't even know
if I'd survive.
But we did!
Now we've got one job,
to find a way out.
I hate to tell you,
but unless there's
another Blood Moon,
there's no way
to escape this place.
And there won't be
another Blood Moon
for, like, a zillion years.
It's useless
to even try to escape.
Well, like my friend
Lloyd always says,
"Ninja never quit."
[heroic music]
[closing theme music]